Henry Robinson Luce Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Speeches and Writings File, 1928-1967 (Box 70-83)
  - Chronological file (Box 70)
    - 1961 (Box 78)
      - Feb., speech notes, Madison Avenue Presbyterian Church, New York, N.Y.
      - Mar., speech notes, Junior Bar Association
      - Aug.
        - Foreword to Why England Slept by John F. Kennedy
        - “The Rule of Law and the Administration of Justice,” American Bar Association
      - Oct., “Why I As a Layman Am Supporting This Project,” National Presbyterian Church and Center conference
    - 1962
      - Jan.
        - “The American Pilgrimage,” YMCA dinner, (2 folders)
        - Speech notes, Madison Avenue Presbyterian Church, New York, N.Y.
      - Feb., speech notes, Trinity College, San Antonio, Tex.
      - Mar.
        - “The Title Deeds of Freedom,” Westminster College, Fulton, Mo.
        - “Anti-Adjustment,” Arizona Citizens for Strengthening Public Education
      - Apr., “All my life... ,” YMCA breakfast (Box 79)
      - May
        - “The Title Deeds of Freedom,” College of Wooster, Wooster, Ohio For additional material see Container 64, Wooster, College of
        - “We Are Such Stuff,” Kit Kat Club, Columbus, Ohio
      - June, “Challenges to the Church,” Princeton Theological Seminary, Princeton, N.J.
      - Nov., “Religion in an Age of Science,” St. James Church
    - 1963
      - Jan., “The Rule of Law,” Canadian Club
      - July, “On this platform... ,” Peace Conference
      - Oct.
        - “I have been hearing... ,” Adelphi University, Garden City, N.Y.
        - “I am happy to... ,” Brick Presbyterian Church, New York, N.Y., annual dinner (Box 80)
      - Nov., “This must be... ,” Prescott College, Phoenix, Ariz.
    - 1964
      - Apr.
        - “One of the characteristics... ,” National Conference of Christians and Jews
        - “The opening of the... ,” Southwestern Legal Foundation
      - May, “Today is a great day... ,” Rotary International
      - June, “I want to talk... ,” Hotchkiss School, Lakeville, Conn.
      - Oct., “Two Assurances of Faith,” Luce Chapel, Tunghai University, Taichung, Taiwan
    - 1965
      - Jan., “It is indeed an honor... ,” bar association, Maricopa County
        - “Dr. Sockman, the honorable... ,” Japan International Christian University Committee
        - “It is a truism... ,” Churchmen's dinner
      - May
        - “There is an old... ,” bar association, Memphis, Tenn.
        - “This is a very... ,” United Board for Christian Higher Education in Asia (Box 81)
        - “There is an old... ,” bar association, Los Angeles, Calif.
      - Sept., “World Law in a New World,” Washington World Conference on World Peace Through Law
      - Dec., “Trans-Pacific Dialogue,” Commonwealth Club, San Francisco, Calif.
    - 1966
      - Feb., “The East and the West - - Basic Differences,” St. John's College, Santa Fe, N.M.
      - May
        - “The East and the West - - Basic Differences,” Arizona State University, Tempe, Ariz.
        - “Providence,” Society of Colonial Wars
      - June, “The Great Society - - Without Cheers,” William Penn College, Oskaloosa, Iowa (Box 82)
      - Oct.
        - Speech notes, Yale-in-China trustee dinner
        - Speech research for “The Secular City,” Madison Avenue Presbyterian Church, New York, N.Y.
      - Dec., “The Pursuit of Significance,” College of Wooster, Wooster, Ohio For additional material see Container 64, Wooster, College of
    - 1967, Feb., “The East and the West - - Basic Differences,” University of California, Santa Barbara, Calif.
  - Miscellaneous writings
    - Book manuscript in segments (partially incorporated in The Ideas of Henry Luce, edited by John K. Jessup, 1969)
      - Drafts
        - Holograph, undated, (2 folders)
        - Typescripts, 1966 (Box 83)
      - Research material, 1966
    - Diary notes, 1940, 1947
    - Essays
      - “Poverty: A Memo for Cursory Research,” 1967
      - Recollections
        - “The Rim of Asia,” 1964
        - Republican nominations for the presidency, 1964
    - Inquiries from publishers and editors about memoirs, 1964-1966
    - Notes
      - “On Communist Manifesto ” and Nikita Krushchev speech, 1962
      - Kennedy, John F., 1960-1965
      - Miscellaneous, 1966-1967
      - Phoenix, Ariz., desk, 1967
      - Religion and education, 1966
      - Ridgefield, Conn., desk, circa 1946
      - Science and religion, 1965
- Financial Papers, 1917-1967 (Box 83-99)
  Bank statements, accounts, budgets, correspondence, and memoranda relating to personal financial affairs and property management.
  Arranged alphabetically by type of material or subject and chronologically therein.
  - Automobiles, 1935-1939, 1960, (2 folders) (Box 83)
  - Bank accounts For additional material see Oversize (Box 84)
    - Buenos Aires, Argentina, 1942
    - Hanover Bank, New York, N.Y., 1938, 1955
    - Miscellaneous, 1934-1956
    - Morgan and Co., Paris, France, 1935-1937
    - National City Bank, New York, N.Y., 1935
    - Putnam Trust, Greenwich, Conn., 1936-1937
  - Bills, Waldorf-Astoria Hotel, New York, N.Y., 1943-1945, (2 folders)
  - Bond purchases, U.S. Treasury, 1943
  - Budgets and household expenses, 1936-1941
  - Cash books, 1945-1960 See Oversize
  - Contributions
    - Correspondence
      - Alphabetical file
        - American-Korean Foundation, 1952-1961
        - American Red Cross, 1948-1965
        - American Shakespeare Festival, 1954-1960
        - Arizona charities, 1958-1967, (2 folders)
        - Boy Scouts of America, 1948-1965 (Box 85)
        - Boys' Clubs of America, 1948-1965
        - Boys' Towns of Italy, 1954-1955
        - British-American Hospital of Spain, 1951-1954
        - Brooks School, North Andover, Mass., 1963-1965
        - Canadian corporations, 1961
        - Catholic Relief Services, 1953-1956
        - Colgate University, Colgate, N.Y., 1951-1962
        - Connecticut charities, miscellaneous, 1936-1964, (2 folders)
        - Connecticut Council of Churches, 1951-1955
        - English-Speaking Union, 1948-1967
        - Escuela Agricola Panamericana, 1963-1966
        - Federation of Protestant Welfare, 1949-1961
        - Harvard University, Cambridge, Mass., 1957-1964
        - Hunter College, New York, N.Y., 1955-1959 (Box 86)
        - Institute for Creative Research, 1950-1957
        - Institute for the Crippled, 1949-1963
        - Legal Aid Society, 1949-1950
        - Manhattanville Community Centers, New York, N.Y., 1948-1965
        - Museum of the City of New York, New York, N.Y., 1953-1961
        - National Foundation for Infantile Paralysis, 1949-1952
        - National Mental Health Foundation, 1947-1954
        - Near East College Association, 1950-1958
        - New Hartford Presbyterian Church, New Hartford, N.Y., 1954-1965
        - New York City Cancer Committee, 1949-1963
        - New York Prison Association, 1948-1953
        - New York University, Bellevue Medical Center, New York, N.Y., research of Milton Rosenbluth, 1945-1965
        - Overseas Press Club, 1952-1966
        - Philharmonic Symphony Society of New York, 1950-1955
        - Pierpont-Morgan Library, New York, N.Y., 1949-1962
        - Presbyterian Church in the U.S.A., 1948-1967
        - Ridgefield Community Center, Ridgefield, Conn., 1954-1963
        - St. Ann's Chapel, San Francisco, Calif., 1950-1965
        - South Carolina charities, 1944-1950
        - Tolstoi Foundation, 1953
        - United Hospital Fund, 1947-1966 (Box 87)
        - United States Committee for the United Nations, 1954, 1961
        - United Negro College Fund, 1947-1965
        - Visiting Nurses Service, 1948-1966
      - Deductible contributions
        - 1944-1947, (5 folders)
        - 1948-1953, (7 folders) (Box 88)
        - 1954-1964, (11 folders) (Box 89)
        - 1965-1967, (3 folders) (Box 90)
      - Nondeductible contributions, 1945-1966, (3 folders)
      - Political
        - 1936-1948
        - 1949-1967, (6 folders) (Box 91)
    - Data and memoranda, 1952-1967, (14 folders) (Box 92)
    - General, 1933-1943, (7 folders) (Box 93)
    - Lists, A-Z, 1938-1967, (2 folders) (Box 94)
  - Customs, 1936-1939
  - Household accounts
    - Brednor Farms, Gladstone, N.J., 1935
    - Greenwich, Conn., house
      - General, 1936-1940, (2 folders)
      - Remodeling, 1938-1939
    - Mepkin Plantation, Moncks Corner, S.C., 1939-1954, (5 folders) (Box 95)
    - Phoenix, Ariz., 1958-1967
    - Ridgefield, Conn.
      - General, 1946-1966, (2 folders)
      - Swimming pool, 1946-1960, (2 folders) (Box 96)
    - Stamford, Conn., house, 1936-1938
  - Insurance, 1935-1937
  - Legal council, 1936-1937, 1944-1954
  - Personal expenses
    - 1935-1940, (6 folders)
    - 1941-1945, (6 folders) (Box 97)
  - Real estate file (Box 98)
    - Country property
      - Connecticut, 1935-1939, (4 folders)
      - New Jersey, 1932-1933
    - Hawaii, 1965-1966
    - Mepkin Plantation, Moncks Corner, S.C., 1936-1951, (3 folders)
    - Miscellaneous transactions, 1945-1961 (Box 99)
    - New York, N.Y., 1935-1961
    - Ridgefield, Conn., 1958-1965
    - Yeamans Hall Club cottage, Charleston, S.C., 1958-1962
  - Stocks
    - Canadian Colonial Airways, 1939
    - Kommer, Rudolf, account #71, Belden & Co., 1937-1939, (2 folders)
    - Mercury Theater, New York, N.Y., 1937-1938
    - Time, inc.
      - Gifts, 1950-1951
      - Loan from Roy E. Larsen, 1935-1939
  - Stocks, taxes, and loans, miscellaneous correspondence, 1936-1952, 1962
- Miscellany, 1920-1967 (Box 100-107)
  Biographical data, office file relating to management of Luce's properties and staff, honorary degrees and awards, guest and gift lists, correspondence, memoranda, and printed material relating to travels.
  Arranged alphabetically by type of material and chronologically therein.
  - Articles and books about Luce, 1949-1964 (Box 100)
  - Awards
    - Certificates, 1934-1962
    - Correspondence, 1935-1967
    - Decorations, 1935-1967
    - Honorary citizenship, Oskaloosa, Iowa, 1965
    - Honorary degrees
      - 1938, Rollins College, Winter Park, Fla.
      - 1941, Boston University, Boston, Mass.
      - 1942, Grinnell College, Grinnell, Iowa
      - 1942, Hamilton College, Hamilton, N.Y.
      - 1945, Syracuse University, Syracuse, N.Y.
      - 1948, Colgate University, Colgate, N.Y.
      - 1949, Rutgers University, New Brunswick, N.J.
      - 1951, College of Idaho, Caldwell, Idaho
      - 1952, Lafayette College, Easton, Pa.
      - 1953, Temple University, Philadelphia, Pa.
      - 1954, Occidental College, Los Angeles, Calif.
      - 1961, Springfield College, Springfield, Mass., and University of Arizona, Tucson, Ariz. (Box 101)
      - 1965, Williams College, Williamstown, Mass.
      - 1966, Yale University, New Haven, Conn.
      - 1967, Westminster College, Fulton, Mo.
  - Luce family
    - Correspondence, 1963-1967
    - Genealogy, 1955-1966
  - Medical treatment, 1956-1963
  - Memberships, directorships, and related material, 1929-1960, (2 folders)
  - Office files
    - Biographical sketches
      - 1947-1961, (3 folders)
      - 1962-1967, with indexes, (2 folders) (Box 102)
    - Christmas file
      - Card selection, 1948
      - Gifts and thank yous, 1959
      - Lists and memoranda
        - 1958-1962, (6 folders)
        - 1963-1967, (5 folders) (Box 103)
    - Household management
      - 1936, River House apartment, New York, N.Y.
      - 1936-1945, staff memoranda
      - 1946-1961, Gladys Freeman
      - 1956, Villa Taverna, Rome, Italy
      - 1958-1959, television set, New York, N.Y.
      - 1966, Honolulu, Hawaii
    - Lists
      - Friends and acquaintances, 1957
      - Miscellaneous, 1954-1957
    - Memoranda (Box 104)
      - Bailey, Wesley, 1943-1944
      - Bourne, Russell, 1954-1956
      - Crider, James L., and Allen Grover, 1946
      - Finch, Edward K. C. (“Kip”), 1947-1953
      - Hehmeyer, Alexander (“Fritz”), 1941-1943
      - Nollen, Emmeline, 1958-1966
    - Newspaper clippings, 1964-1966
    - Parties
      - Miscellaneous, 1943-1966
      - Tsaing, Ting Fu, dinner honoring, 1965
    - Records
      - Army, military draft, and social security, 1920-1945
      - Passports, 1935-1966
      - Residences, 1936-1960
      - Voting, 1942-1962
    - Trips (Box 105)
      - 1935, Havana, Cuba
      - 1936, Yacht Elfreda
      - 1936, Yacht North Wind
      - 1937, Hawaii, house rental
      - 1938-1939, Europe and Bermuda
      - 1940-1941, 1944, Colorado; Sun Valley, Idaho; West Coast; Florida
      - 1945, China
        - Messages conveyed and war souvenirs
        - Yorktown (Aircraft carrier), mementoes (Box 106)
      - 1946, New Hampshire
      - 1947-1948, Chicago, Ill.; Cleveland, Ohio; Kentucky; Washington, D.C.; Rio de Janero, Brazil; and White Sulphur Springs, W.Va.
      - 1950-1952, South Carolina; Dallas, Tex.; Mexico City, Mexico; Palo Alto, Calif.; and miscellaneous
      - 1953-1954, Mediterranean, Far East, and miscellaneous
      - 1956-1959, Italy, Virgin Islands, and miscellaneous
      - 1960-1961, Greece and India
      - 1962, Australia; Majorca; Mexico; Seattle, Wash.; and Denver, Colo.
      - 1963, Rome, Italy, and Athens, Greece
      - 1965, Hawaii and Charleston, S.C. (Box 107)
      - 1965, Yale University, New Haven, Conn. (Chubb Fellow)
      - 1966, Yale University, New Haven, Conn.; Japan; and Valley Forge and Haverford, Pa.
      - 1966, New Harmony, Ind.; Seattle, Wash.; and Honolulu, Hawaii
    - Wedding presents, 1949
- Addition, 1941 (Box 107-108)
  Correspondence relating to Luce's article, “The American Century,” published in Life, 1941.
  - “The American Century,” correspondence (Box 107)
    - 1941
      - Feb. 14-22, (5 folders)
      - Feb. 23-May 29, (15 folders) (Box 108)
    - Undated
- Oversize, 1945-1960 (Box OV 1-OV 2)
  Cash books.
  Arranged alphabetically by name of financial institution.
  - Financial Papers (Box OV 1)
    - Cash books (Container 84)
      - Banco di Roma, Rome, Italy, 1953-1957, including correspondence and notes, 1953-1959, (2 vols.)
      - Central Hanover Bank & Trust, New York, N.Y.
        - 1945-1949
        - 1949-1952 (Box OV 2)
      - First National Bank & Trust, Ridgefield, Conn., 1948-1952
      - New York Trust, New York, N.Y., 1945-1960, including stocks, 1945-1957
      - Trust Co. of Old Greenwich, Conn., 1944-1948